IC Pential IPO which has been the
hottest topic for the market in 2025.  Now this IPO is going to be
listed on
Friday, 19th December and just
before the listing, there seems to be a tremendous rise in the grey market premium.
Targets are being seen emerging from many brokers
and many updates are coming.
But leaving all that aside, in this video we will
cover what we should do in this IPO on the listing day.
Should I stay in it
or exit?
Where can the listing be?  How much can I get for a listing
?  And what should be done in the short term and long term
?  Let me tell you, the video will be a little long.
Generally, from the videos we make, there are a
lot of details that we want to
share with you so that you
can decide what to choose in long term, short term or
listing gains.
I will tell you everything.  Stay tuned to the end of the video
so that you can understand all the information properly.
Before I start with the details, let me
tell you all that guys, we are not a civil
service advisor. Whatever details are
shared here are for educational purposes and for
international purposes, which are
made on publicly available data.
If you have to take any decision, do
your own research. If possible, take
advice from your financial advisor before taking any
decision. Let's come back and
start with the details of ICIC Pensal Mutual
Fund IPO. I think there is
no need to tell you about the business.  There are some basic
points that I would like to cover,
first of all, its size is ₹162.65
crore which is a large size IPO and will be
very high in the free float market.
Apart from that, the second most important thing is
reservation in this IPO.  Of the
reservations made, 47.50% was
reserved for QIBs.  This 47.50%
also included reservations for QIBS who
place their shares just a day before the IPO opening
and also for those who
place their shares after the IPO opening.  That is, those who
invest before the IPO opens are
called anchors and those who
invest after the IPO opens are called QIBs.
But both are the same.  So there is a condition in this
that whatever anchors participate,
they cannot exit even after the IPO opens.
Their 50% quota is
locked in for 30 days and the
remaining 50% is locked in for 90 days, which means they
cannot exit and those who
invested money before the IPO have a
lock in of 6 months, they cannot exit
and in 47.50%,
28.5%
anchors have invested around Rs 322 crore, something will come out, if
you withdraw then 28.5% is
locked in for 30 days and 90 days, they
cannot exit but the
remaining 19% are QIBs.  But
among those QIBs, some anchors might have also
participated and some anchors did
not participate.  Have come as direct
QIB.  So those
anchors who have come directly as QIB and have
not participated can exit on Day One.
So approximately 30 to 35% will
go into lock in.  The remainder is free
float that can be exited.  And
apart from that, brother, in the HAI category of 14.25%, about
4 to 5% are not long term investors.   Have come
purely for listing.   If there are
retailers then the goods will be taken out from here also.
Approximately, let's say 4 to 5% at
least will go.  After that, 33.25%
is owned only by retailers.  So this
is also included in free float.  Exit can be done from here also.
After that, there was another 5% which
was for the shareholder category and
those in the shareholder category would also mostly
withdraw.  So, when you calculate overall, out of the
shares worth Rs 10,600 crore,
approximately 50% or more than 50% can be
exited.  This means that the
free float in the market is too large for exits to occur.
And I explained this thing to you now
because it is going to be used in the future.
So if I had told you to keep this thing in mind further, there would have been
confusion.  Now many people
here also had the problem that they did not get allotment in the share holder category.
Allotment was not received in the retail category and there were many problems.
So actually, was there
any problem in not getting the allotment or did you get a fair
allotment or not,
we have also made a video on that, the
link is in the description, you
can go and watch it, everything about the allotment of
ICICI has been told, you will understand about all the other IPOs as well.
So till now we have covered this very
important data of ICICI IPO.
This will help us in this matter whether we want to go for long term or
not or want to
get out through listing.  Now it becomes necessary to do peer comparison
because at what
valuation are we taking the IPO.  It is important to know at what
valuation it can go up.
Now if you remember a few things from our IPO
review video,
one of the things was that this is the second largest AMC
company which holds a market share of 13.2%.
And then at number three
comes HDFC AMC which holds a market share of 11.5%.
And first of all is SBI
AMC. I have taken the name of SBI at the last even though it is
number one.  Why?  Because
it is not listed.  So
currently there are only two listed players in the market.  One is
ICIC which is going to happen.  One HDFC which
is already listed and ICICI is a big company
which has data of approximately Rs 10.75 lakh crore
and this is the data till September 2025.
AVM manages assets under management.
Meaning, the more AVMs one manages, the more
profit he will make.
The more she will earn.
HDFC AMC is at second place with a value of Rs 8.7 lakh crore and this data
may vary at different places.  This has to be taken
care of.  Now,
HDFC AMC should obviously give a little better price than what the market is offering,
this is genuine because it is a
bigger company and is managing more assets than this.  She
will earn more than this.
If we compare the same thing
with HDFC or SBI, then there is complete data which is the
profit before tax data.  In this you
can see that the company which makes the highest pre-tax
profit is ICIC Pro.
SBI is at second place and
HDFC is at third place.  Ok?  This is all AMC.
After that you can watch the rest of AMC.  This is the
data before filing the tax.  If we compare the
data till March 2024 with the
data till March 2025, there is a
jump of Rs 835 crore in ICICI Pro.  After that
you can see the rest also.  If we do peer comparison
as per PE ratio, then you
can see that its PE is coming out to be 40.37.  Among
its other peers,
HDFC has a PE of 45.20.
Ok?  There is no need to compare him further.
Because the rest of the companies are
small.  So there is still a gap somewhere.
If we compare it with HDFC AMC, it can get this much.
As per its price at
today's closing, the listing
here is coming out to be 15 to 20%, which means
that this much listing can be positive.  At
present, we are
comparing all the data and
according to that, we can get at least 15 to 20% discount
and it can also increase a little.  If
you actually understood the things that I have told you, then it is a
very good thing.  If you don't understand then let me
tell you its short version.
So let's go and see the final update.  So
first of all, according to the comparison that we have done just now, even
if the listing is done at 15-20%,
HDFC looks good
in comparison to the current price to earnings
ratio of HDFC.  So
where could the listing be?  The
target given by others.  Some have
given for long term.  The target came out to be 2900 by March 2027.
Just received from a broker.
Ok?  Given by a broker.
Which we have shared on Telegram.
You can go and check it out.
You will find the link to Telegram in the description.  And
we have also shared its GMP on Telegram.
Which seems to be coming out to be 480 to 490.  There is an
approximate gain of 23%.   It was
also important to tell this GMP.  And I will
also show you the report of Rs 2900.
Look here, we have posted it, Ace
Securities has said that there will be an
upside of 34% till March 2027 and
in yesterday's video I had already told you about the 3000
issue, if you have seen yesterday's video then it is
very good, otherwise go and see two
old videos, in that it has been told
who was giving the target of 3000, what is it,
everything is fine, now let us see our things, do
follow Twitter where the
update of Dekh Lo was also given and the
use of this update of Msho is also to come, I will tell you later, for
now let us come back to the topic and we were
talking about where the listing can happen,
regarding which I have shown you all those
things.  According to me,
my prediction for listing is
if the market chair does it or the market is
good or its segment is good.
Ok?  So in such conditions
it can go from 2600 2650 to 2700 and
in some conditions 2720 30 will also be justified.
But if it is getting listed more than that then
there I will say brother that yes game play has happened
purely and it will be visible directly
because till here the listing will be around 24
to 25%, if we
talk about ₹2700 then
listing is happening above that then brother ₹20-₹30 above but if it is happening
more than that then the game can say
that suppose it is getting 28%-30% then that will seem a bit
unexpected to me, now
what can I do for the things which are not looking good, we will
see where the listing will happen, where will it happen as per
your opinion,
you can also tell in the comment section, as of now my prediction is still
incomplete, so this is my listing on the positive side,
if there is a little negative
turn as well.  So I think at the very
most there could be listings around 250050 2600
below.  Now even if it is being
listed below 2550,
I will still say that the sentiments are negative
because of that.  But if it is listed below 2500 then
that too will be unexpected.
I don't think something like this would happen
even after such a good subscription.  But
if there are too many sell orders in the pre-opening session,
then a lower listing can be
expected.
You will also plan your exit in the pre-opening session.  So
if you know how to exit the pre-opening session then it is okay.  If you don't understand then
comment.  I have the video ready.
I will post the video
of the pre-opening session shortly.  So if
you want something then tell me quickly in the comments.
I will upload the video of how it is
taken out in the pre-opening session.  So
if more people exit in the pre-opening session, the
price will be hit there too.  So
this is my prediction.
What do you think your prediction is?  Where
can it be listed or what will be the matter as per
your opinion, you can tell in the comments.
Whoever is positive,
your name will be highlighted in the next video I make.  The
gains we have seen in Meesho have almost
doubled.  Could it be money
?  No, look, you will have to
go to Telegram once again.  It is
very difficult that what happened in Meesho IPO will happen here.
Why?  Because if we come down once, you
can see that the free float of Meesho is
6% equity.  Free to trade
free float.  The rest have kept the
goods hidden.  So what happens in such a condition when free float
is low and demand is high
?  The price increases.  Same thing has
happened here.  But the first lock-in, which I
told you in the beginning, is for
30 days and the lock-in is ending on January 6, so there will be
some selling there,
after that it will also end on 90 days and if in between
someone exits or the market
becomes negative, then that is also a scenario.  So this
free float in Meesho is very less.  It is 6%
and here 40 to 50% was coming out.   Only
more than 50 were coming out.  Ok
?  At least 30-40% is in the worst condition.
So we cannot compare it with that.
What should be done now?  Because the free float
is very high here, the chances of getting bookings are
very high.  Even in this IPO,
if you were sitting live with me on the day of subscription, when it
was closing, you
saw how many people were there, brother, they were sitting with one CR
to two CR for subscription, so
they are not going to go in the long term.
Their purpose is only booking.
So maximum people will try to book here.
In such a situation, the listing that we are seeing may
also be wiped out.
Maybe, let's say, 20% of the listings that are being viewed may
turn into 10%.  If you
can take the risk then only you should
go for long term and in the condition that the market falls,
brother,
you will have to take a minimum risk of 10 to 15% from its price band,
if you are going for long term
and I would also say in short term
that even if your plan is for at least 3-6 months,
we will have to take this risk.
If you don't want to take it then you have to
book it in the listing.  Now
what is the way to maximize listing?
Look, I
come live for you on the day the IPO is listed.  I come
live on every IPO day.
I will come live tomorrow also and I will come a little early tomorrow.  Meaning I will
try to come by 9 10 9:15.  I
will give you its update on Telegram.  Join Telegram
link in the description comment section.
So when I come live,
I will tell you one SL of this,
brother, where to place the SL.  Suppose you want to
partially maximize your gains
but want to display safely, then
exit in the pre-opening session itself or
exit 50% just after listing.
Sell ​​the remaining 50% quantity i.e. three shares.  If you have got two
lots then one lot.  If you have got four lots, then you
can make it two lots or you
can make it one, two, three as per your convenience.  So
you exited 40 to 50% quantity.   I
put SL on the remaining quantity.
Your gain in SL may be slightly less.
Suppose it is listed at ₹2700.
We saw volatility.  After deciding that,
suppose we decided SL of ₹264050.
So let's say it hits ₹2650.
So we took the entire quantity and exited.
So here the risk between ₹2700 and ₹2650 is the
risk of your profit decreasing.  But if it goes to 282900 then your
profit will increase.  In this way, you
can do it on full quantity or you
can do it even after booking half quantity.
So according to me it would be better to release it in the pre-opening session
and if
you have more quantity then if
you want a video of the pre-opening session then
tell me, after this video is posted it will take
about half an hour or 40 minutes to
edit and post it
and this is the strategy, if anything else happens then we will
discuss it live, latest
GMP, after this whatever happens will be
posted on Twitter and I hope
I have explained it to you in a full flash manner in the video,
what is your decision,
what can be the listing according to you, comment on all this,
I will read everyone's comments and will
reply to everyone, if you liked the video then do
not forget to like, subscribe and share, see you
in the next video.  Bye, take